Git Branching

Reference: coderefinery.org  -> lessons -> git branching

# display the start symbol in short:  export PS1="$ "


create a new folder "recipe"
create two new txt files "instruction.txt" and "ingredients.txt"

git add .
git commit -m "adding ingredients and instructions"
git status

make changes on txt files
git diff


git config --global alias.graph "log --all --graph --decorate --oneline"  # put git log history, one per line
git graph

git branch

git branch experiment
git checkout experiment

git branch -d branch_name  # delete a branch, should be in another branch

git checkout [a former commit hash]
git graph  # see where HEAD is located

in newer git version
git switch experiment     # change branch to "experiment"
git restore ingredients.txt  # undo the change, restore the file to the latest commit


# stay in master
git merge experiment
git branch --merged # show which branches are merged into the current branch, master

# delete branches (clean up the graph)
First, check if branches have been merged
git branch --merged
git branch -d branch1 branch2  # can delete a list of branches

add a tag to a commit
The tag is attached to a commit, not a branch (the branch pointer can move forward, but the tag will stay pointing to the commit when it was made)

git tag --annotate nobel-2017 -m "recipe I made for the 2017 Nobel banquet"
git show nobel-2017
# we can also checkout a tag
git checkout nobel-2017
# the tag is local
to make it online
git push --tag ?? (check it for a correct command format)

# Solve conficts
If a conflict occurs when merge a branch
if check the affect file(s), we will see the changes in different branches
If want to abort
git merge --abort  # this will still keep two branches separate, without the above inserted comments in the conflicted file(s)

# in case we are in our branch, i.e., branch0, to merge branch1
git merge -s recursive -Xours branch1   # in case of conflicts, always adopt changes in our branch (branch0 here)
git merge -s recursive -Xtheirs branch1 # Or, in case of conflicts, always adopt changes in their branch (branch1 here)


Suggested branch naming rules:
Use "developer_name/feature_name" as the branch name

git flow
www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/comparing-workflows

